<!--==========================================================================-->
<!-- Copyright (c) 2000-2004,  Elastos, Inc.  All Rights Reserved.-->
<!--==========================================================================-->

    <?xml version = "1.0" encoding="GB2312" ?>
    <?xml:stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/xsl/xsl_e/methodmanual.xsl"?><manpage>
<volume>Synchronization</volume>
<interface>Mutex</interface><method> TryLock </method>
    <description>
        <para>
            Attempts to get Mutex Lock object.
        </para>
    </description>
    <syntax>
        <return_val>ECODE</return_val>
        <parameters>
            <api_param>
            	<param_inout>[in]</param_inout>
                <param_type> uint_t </param_type>
                <param_name> uTicks</param_name>
                <param_note>
                    <para>
                       Specifies a time delay, the unit is tick. If <i>uTicks</i> is zero, the function returns at once.
                       If Mutex object is obtained, returns S_OK, otherwise returns S_TIMED_OUT.
                    </para>
                </param_note>
            </api_param>
        </parameters>
    </syntax>

	<return>

    	<table>
            <th>
                <td>Return Value</td>
                <td>Hex Value</td>
                <td>Description</td>
            </th>
             <tr>
                <td>S_OK</td>
                <td>0x00000000</td>
                <td> Function succeeds in attempting to get Mutex Lock object. </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>S_TIMED_OUT</td>
                <td>0x00060003</td>
                <td> 
                	Wait time exceeds specified time-out period; i.e, the current thread cannot get the
                	mutex object within the time-out period. 
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>S_INTERRUPTED</td>
                <td>0x00060014</td>
                <td>Interrupted while waiting for Mutex object.</td>
            </tr>

        </table>
        <para>References <link url="/sdk/hresult.htm">ECODE</link> related help for details.</para>
	</return>

	<remarks>
		<para>
           		This function is used for attempting to get Mutex Lock object. If Mutex Lock object has been
           		occupied by another thread, the calling thread will get into waiting state till it succeeds
           		in occupying the Mutex Lock object. If the waiting time is over, the calling thread will
           		finish waiting and return S_TIMED_OUT. If <i>uTicks</i> is 0, this member function returns immediately.
           		If the calling thread occupies the Mutex object, it will return S_OK, otherwise it will return 
           		S_TIMED_OUT. If Mutex Lock object does not have any ownership, the calling thread will occupy the 
           		Mutex Lock object, and the function will return at once. If the calling thread occupies the Mutex 
           		Lock object, the function will return too. The calling thread should call the <link url="Unlock.htm">
           		Mutex::Unlock</link> function accordingly to release the Mutex Lock object. Thread 
           		can be interrupted while waiting for mutex object.
		</para>
	</remarks>

    <requirements>
        <system>
            <system_name>
				Elastos 2.0 or later
	    	</system_name>
        </system>
    </requirements>
</manpage>